Taylor Lightbourne

Full Stack Developer and UI/UX Designer Atlanta, GA | (240) 480-1825 taylorlightbourne@gmail.com

Creative software engineer with the ability to pick up new languages and technologies as needed. Prior to being a software engineer, I worked as an administrative coordinator for a construction company where I worked alongside project managers to ensure assignments were completed efficiently.

Software Development Skills

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Node.js, Express.js, PostgreSQL, Sequelize, Bootstrap, and Figma.

Education

DigitalCrafts | Certificate in Software Engineering | Atlanta, GA

March 2021 - June 2021

 Software engineering training program covering full-stack development including, but not limited to JavaScript and Python. The program includes an emphasis on cutting-edge frameworks like React/Redux and server-side technologies including Node.js, Express.js, and PostgreSQL.

Towson University | B.S. in Advertising and Public Relations | Towson, MD

August 2013 – May 2017

Software Development and UI/UX Design Projects

Planned the design of these projects with sketches, user flow diagrams, sitemaps, and wireframes. These techniques helped build a prototype, which was used to assemble the user interface based around the goal of the project.

Park Rangers

HTML, CSS, Node.js, Express.js, Postgres

- Worked on a team alongside five other students to develop a full stack application that allows users to create itineraries that lists parks they would like to explore.
- The website uses the National Park's API to provide users with information on parks across the United States.

Weather App

HTML. CSS. JavaScript

- Created an application that uses OpenWeather's API to provide the current weather for a specific zip code.
- The user can enter a zip code for the current temperature of the location to be displayed, along with a description of the weather condition. A picture to represent the current weather condition and time of day will also appear.

Tip Calculator

HTML, CSS, JavaScript

- Created a multi functional application that is useful for various calculating needs.
- The application includes a basic calculator, a tip calculator, and a suggested tip calculator.

ToDo App

HTML, CSS, Node.js, Express.js

- Individual project that provides a way to create, edit, and delete tasks from a to do list.
- Full stack application that requires users to create an account in order to login.
- Passport is implemented for user authentication, along with bcrypt for password security.

Professional Work Experience

Co-Owner of an Art and Massage Studio | Therapeutic Tranquility | Newnan, GA

October 2020 - Present

- Communicate and coordinate with customers to plan their events, while providing excellent customer service throughout the process.
- Create all branding to advertise the business through the company's website and social media accounts.

Administrative Coordinator | PCM Services | Columbia, MD

March 2019 - October 2020

- Managed the asphalt, concrete, and line striping coordinating division.
- Participated in meetings that used scrum and agile methodology to communicate with team members across multiple departments.
- Reviewed and processed contracts for project commitments that were also entered into Vista, along with other programs to store documents and track project progression.